I am a professional golfer and a member of the Korean Ladies Professional Golf Association.
I play in a league which would be an equivalent of Minor League in baseball.
However, I don't think that my passion and dreams are minor league.
So, to achieve my passion and dreams, I have been practicing in my field.
But I feel like I have fallen behind and getting farther away from my dreams.
Also, I feel that my family is sacrificing too much for me.
My conviction of "I can do this" sometimes becomes a question of "Can I do this?"
I believe I can overcome my doubts because my conviction is stronger than my skepticism .
I am hoping that you can advise and encourage me.
Why don't you give it up?
But I want to continue.
Listening to you and assessing your mental state, I think it will be difficult for you to become a top athlete.
Your metal focus needs to be exceptionally strong to be a top athlete.
Your focus needs to be such that you don't think about anything, even about succeeding.
Only then can you rise to the next level.
But you are already being greedy about succeeding.
You are tormented because you are trying to achieve more than you are currently capable of.
If so, it will be difficult for you to succeed.
I am not a psychic nor a fortune teller.
Instead of making your family suffer, it is better to set some ground rules now.
It's best to listen to me and do this.
If you still want to try, just do it for one more year.
Ask your parents, "Please, support me for just 1 more year. I will give up if it doesn't work out."
And from then on, you need to do away with all distractions and focus on golf like your life depended on it. If you succeed, great. If you don't, give up.
People drag out taking state exams and such for years because they don't focus.
They end up wasting time and putting a burden on those around them.
The 1st option is to give up now.
If you still want to try, the 2nd option is to set a time frame.
Decide on exactly 6 months or 1 year, and give up if it doesn't work.
You have a chance if you give it all you've got with no excuses.
If your mind wanders, or you have doubts again, you don't have a chance.
Does this help?
Yes, it's a strong wake-up call.
But my goal this year was to give golf everything I've got.
But you only thought about giving everything.
Are you able to wholly focus on golf, or are you also spending time doing other things?
I thought I was controlling my distractions to some extent.
And I am trying very hard. So I was hoping to get some encouragement.
Just trying hard is not enough.
How can you make a breakthrough simply by trying?
Unless you are a natural born athlete, trying hard is not enough.
You have to give it all you've got.
You have to work so hard that you bring yourself to tears when you think about your efforts.
Is your coach or your parents deeply inspired by how much effort your are putting in?
Somewhat inspired, but I don't think they are deeply inspired.
That's not enough. They should be so insprired that they encourage you to continue even if you say you will give it up.
Here is an example. I don't usually ask for donations from our members.
But they still donate. Why?
I have campaigned to help those starving in North Korea, shedding tears and and going on a 70-day hunger strike for them.
Some members donate because they are afraid that I will starve to death before the North Koreans.
If you commit whole-heartedly like this, you can attain a deep insight.
That's why I can understand the overall situation in North Korea even when a small incident happens there.
Are all of you in the audience experts on marital problems? Or am I?
It's you, right?
You are the experts on child-rearing, not me.
Did I ever get married? Did I ever have or raise a child?
But people kept asking me about these matters, so I started reflecting on them.
And when I did, there wasn't much to them.
Why? Because Buddhism basically deals with the problem of managing the human mind. Right?
And doesn't the human mind function within our relationships with each other?
The fact is marital relationships have only 1% difference from other relationships.
Parent-child relationships also have about 1% difference.
It's like although humans and champanzees seem quite different, genetically the difference is only 1 %...
I take a particular type of relationship and reflect on it by examining a great number of cases similar to it.
You only know about a handful of cases, while I know about a countless number of cases. Right?
As a result, I have a deep insight about all kinds of relationships. When two young people come to me and say they want to get married,
I ask them why they like each other. When I listen to their answers,
I can tell right away whether the relationship will last or end in three years.
You can predict certain outcomes if you're aware of the principles of life.
If you smoke 3 cigarettes during the 30 minutes you talk with me, I can predict that you will also smoke tomorrow.
But it is also possible that you won't. Such possibilities are open to humans.
But in a state of ignorance, people act according to the general prediction, which make them belive in fatalism
If you realize this principle and stop believing in fatalism, the prediction will no longer apply.
That's why the Buddha denied fatalism and showed us the path to enlightenment.
By listening to you, I see that you are not focusing as you should be.
You cannot succeed if you follow your karma or your life habits.
You should give up if you are going to live as your karma dictates.
If you want to overcome your karma, you need to completely change your state of mind.
Simply trying isn't enough.
Set a time frame, and give up if you don't succeed.
You need to be totally focused on your goal.
As I said earlier, you need to wholly devote yourself to it to make a breakthrough.
If you experience something similar to a breakthrough, only then will things change.
Then miracles will start to happen, like making a hole in one.
But not with slow, dragged out practices.
When lighting a match, if you rub the match slowly, it won't light even if you do it 500 times.
If you strike the match, it will light up at once.
If you rub it 500 times and strike it once, you may think that it takes 501 tries to light a match. But it is not so.
It is not good to drag things out. Success depends on how much you focus.
And you should be independent of your family. How old are you?
I am 24 years old.
For a golfer, 24 years old is…
It is a peak age.
A little old to be starting out.
But…
You should have reached your peak performance in your early 20s. Then you could perform well until age 40.
Even if you failed to do it in your early 20s, you could succeed if your family were very wealthy and can keep supporting you.
Telling me about your family's sacrifice means that your family's financial support is not enough. Right?
Yes.
It's like not having enough money when you are gambling.
If you had a lot of money, you could keep on betting.
I assessed the situation as soon as you began talking. So what will you do?
Are you going to give up now and perhaps teach golf and make money to help out your family?
Or are you going to set a time frame and completely commit to golf?
The latter. I've made up my mind.
You gave me two choices, to give up or to give it all I have.
Yes.
I would like to show you how I've changed in a year's time.